Inventory of the The Adagio Press Collection, 1957-1988
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
The Adagio Press Collection 1957-1988
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
94 Ad1
103 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1993.
Scope and Content
Books, cards, letters, envelopes, and other items printed by Leonard F. Bahr (1938-1992), founder and owner of the Adagio Press from 1957-1988; biographical material of various dates about Bahr, check lists of Adagio press items; and a letter to Bahr from Henry Morris and two letters to Norman Forgue from Bahr. The Adagio Press was started in 1956 in Bahr's hometown of Harper Woods, Michigan.
Contents List
- April 22,1993 - July 3,1994., 6 items. (Folder 1)
  Correspondence about the Adagio Press gift given by Christian Vinyard.
- 1968-1993, 8 items. (Folder 2)
  Biographical material about Leonard Bahr.
- 1968-1993, 3 items. (Folder 3)
  . "A Selected Check-List of works printed at Adagio", #1973. Adagio: A Checklist, 1993. ML A Quarterly: "Adagio: The Private Press of Leonard F. Bahr", 1968.
- 1960-1972., 3 items. (Folder 4)
  Two letters: October 31, I960, Leonard Bahr, Detroit, Michigan, to Norman Forgue and July 4, 1964, Leonard [F.] Bahr, Harper Woods, Michigan to [Norman] Forgue, [Chicago, Illinois]. One letter: February] 29,1972, Henry Morris, North Hills, Pennsylvania, to Leonard Bahr, [?], concerning a bill and a personal note to the recipient.
- n.d., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  Type Specimen Book of the Adagio Press.
- 1957., 1 item. (Folder 6)
  Miscellanea fypographica: Notes on Books and Printing, Number Three. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1959., 1 item. (Folder 7)
  How to Build a Poor Man's Morgan Library. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1960., 1 item. (Folder 8)
  Printing in Privacy: A Review of Recent Activity Among American Private Presses. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1961., 1 item. (Folder 9)
  An Intrusion Upon Eternity. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1962., 2 items. (Folder 10.)
  Cordially Yours. The Contemptible Horse. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1963., 1 item. (Folder 11.)
  An Introduction to the Adagio Press. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1964., 5 items. (Folder 12.)
  A Tribute to Anton Bohm and His Work at the Sans Souci Press. The Angel That Didn't Fly. The Spirit of Liberty: An Address by Judge Learned Hand. But the Greatest of These Is Love. ABC Card. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1965., 2 items. (Folder 13.)
  The Spring of the Year. Interpretations and Insinuations. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1966., 1 item. (Folder 14.)
  The Question of Christmas. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1967., 4 items. (Folder 15.)
  Experiments With the Bradley Ornaments (2 copies). The Evolution of Printing Presses From Wood to Metal: An Essay in Tribute to Paul A. Bennett. A Book Collector's Chronicle. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1968., 1 item. (Folder 16.)
  Typographic Embellishers: Some Specimens From the Collection Used at the Adagio Press. The Adagio Press Has Acquired A Different Printing Press. MLA Quarterly. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1969., 1 item. (Folder 17.)
  C-S: The Master Craftsman. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1970., 2 items. (Folder 18.)
  A Few Sentences From the Writings of Robert Lewis Stevenson. A Gathering of Typographic Odds and Ends. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1971., 2 item. (Folder 19.)
  Abetter to Stella: An Epilogue to the Publication C-S: The Master Craftsman. Exchanges. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1972., 70 items. (Folder 20.)
  Alphabet in Color. Antique, Decorated and Kindred Types. Typographic Doodling. Man Errs So Long As He Strives. Adagio is a Private Press. The Tragedy of Life. The Artist of Kauroo. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1972-1973., 1 item. (Folder 21.)
  Christmas Card: In Rivers, the Water That You Touch. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1973., 2 items. (Folder 22.)
  A Manner of Printing. (2 copies) Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1974., 1 item. (Folder 23.)
  Christmas Card: And Now Let Us Believe in the Year That is Given Us. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1975., 2 items. (Folder 24.)
  Christmas Card: Matthew David, Ann and Leonard Bahr wish you a very Merry Christmas. If One Advances. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1976., 6 items. (Folder 25.)
  24 Hours (2 copies). Man Truly Lives (2 copies). Typographia 1 (2 copies). Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1977., 2 items. (Folder 26.)
  The Strength of Fields. Adagio. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1978, 1 item. (Folder 27.)
  Christmas Card: When Shall All Men's Good Be Each Man's Rule. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1979., 3 items. (Folder 28.)
  Typographia 2 (2 copies). Printed by Leonard Bahr. (2 items)
- 1981, 3 items. (Folder 29.)
  To Affect the Quality of the Day (2 copies). Psalm 23. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1982., 1 item. (Folder 30.)
  Proverbs of Hell. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1983., 5 items. (Folder 31.)
  A Paragraph on Paper (2 copies). Taken All in All, The Private Press is Replete With Possibilities (2 copies). Literature Must Struggle With Difficulties. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1984., 2 items. (Folder 32.)
  Various Aspects of Borrowed Books. Bookmark: Borrowers of Books. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1987., 4 items. (Folder 33.)
  . We Will Either Find A Way or Make One (2 copies). Practice is Art (2 copies). Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1988., 1 item. (Folder 34.)
  Universal History. Printed by Leonard Bahr.
- 1994., 1 item. (Folder 35.)
  LFB to PHD, re: C and VH. Printed by the Louisville Contre Coup Press.
- 1967-1982 and n.d. (Folder 36.)
  Envelopes.
- n.d., 23 items. (Folder 36.)
  Christmas Cards: The Approach of Christmas and a New Year. Christmas is Goodwill and Compassion. Christmas: Music Family Friends. I Saw the Night Visions. For low, the Days are Hast'ning On. Hallelujah! For the Lord God Omnipotent Reigneth. How Silently, How Silently, the Wonderful Gift is Given. Joy to You on This Day and Throughout the Year. Oh! Merry Piping Time of Christmas. And Suddenly There Was with the Angel. Merry Christmas! Some Say that Ever 'gainst that Season Comes Wherein Our Savior's Birth is Celebrated. From the Preface to Travels with a Donkey. For I dipt into the Future. Rise, Happy Mourn. The Time Draws Near the Birth of Christ. What is Hope, What is Expectation? Somehow not only for Christmas but All the Long Year Through. Bookmarks: I Rejoice That There Are Owls (2 copies). Calling card of Leonard Bahr (2 copies). Four Ideals. Printed by Leonard Bahr.